# Jeet Vora

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

% https://jeet-dev.vercel.app/

@jeetvora331

in @jeetvora331

### **Frontend Developer Profile**

Highly accomplished and user-focused Front-end Developer adept in collaborating with UX and design teams to plan the technical writing and execution of functional specifications for websites and applications. Experienced in building multi-platform websites using Responsive Web Design

## **Frontend Relevant Projects**

Portfolio Website Personal Portfolio that is visually appealing, modern and dynamic, helping me stand out from the competition. It demonstrates my professional skill set, projects and achievements Link

**SuperThoughts** A social media platform that allows users to create an account, post short messages (thoughts) up to a specific character limit, and engage with other's content through comments. Link

Built with NextJS, TailwindCSS, Firebase Realtime Database

The Smell. E-Commerce Website that allows visitors to login, shop and checkout seamlessly. Providing powerful management tools for website owners. Integrated with Stripe and authO Link

#### **Education**

From 2021 to 2022

Post Graduate Diploma in Computer Application

Maharaja Sayajirao University Baroda

87.92%

From 2017 to 2021

**B.Tech in Electrical Engineering** 

Pandit Deendayal Petroleum University Gandhinagar, India

CGPA 8.64/10

## **Experience**

**Udemy Course Instructor** 2022

Python Weekend Bootcamp 5 Star Instructor

Designed and Created the Curriculum for a 3-Day

Beginner's Python Bootcamp (Link)

From June 2021 to September 2021

Python Developer Internship

Brown Wolf Studio Private Limited Rajkot

Part Time

From February 2021 to March 2021

Website and App Designer

Pandit Deendayal Energy University Gandhinagar

2 Month of Internship where I designed the

complete UI and UX of the WebApp in AdobeXD and

was able to successfully develop it in React

#### **PORTFOLIO WEBSITE**

Personal Portfolio Website Link Click for a better and more immersive portfolio

# **Programming** Languages

experience

HTML | CSS along with Tailwind CSS a utility first, mobile first CSS framework

JavaScript along with React, NextJS

Java (OOP)

**Python** 

#### **Relevant Certifications**

CS-50 Introduction to CS (Harvard University)

Developed **Chrome extension** as Final Project (Certificate), (edX Verified Certificate)

Responsive Web Design certification from freeCodeCamp.org Certification

## **Mini Projects**

**Gradient Generator** Demo

Quality Quotes Demo

Tell a Joke Demo

## **Open Source Contribution**

**matlplotlib (merged)** Solved an issue regarding light graph color on white background <u>Link</u>

**strapi cms (on-going)** Raised issue present in the documentation, which was causing the error during installation <u>Link</u>

#### **Research Publications and Patents**

Design of Novel Time Monitored Touchless Operation using 555 Timer for Automatic Dispenser 5th IEEE International Conference on Recent Advances and Innovations in Engineering-ICRAIE 2020, <u>IEEE Explore</u> DOI:10.1109/ICRAIE51050.2020.9358372

**Design Patent (IPR)** Design Patent on Soap Dispenser, Application No. 332436-001 (approved)

## **Positions of Responsibility**

From August Core Technical Member , Design Head

2018 to August Cretus - Robotics and Automation club of PDPU

2020 Gandhinagar, India

From 2019 to General Secretary

2020 Electrical's Students' and Professionals' Association-PDPU

Gandhinagar, India

From 2018 to Design Head

2020 Society of Mathematics (SOM) - PDPU Gandhinagar, India

## **Achievements / Hackathons**

**2nd Runner up at Lets Hack COVID-19** Secured this position on Automatic Sanitizer Dispenser we also derived a research paper from the project and published it at IEEE Conference

**Best Prototype Winner at Lets Hack 2.0 (2019)** Won this award on automatic solar panel cleaner prototype! (This Round was part of Smart India Hackathon)

**Completed Hacktober Fest 2020 Challenge** Successfully completed the challenge in 15 days and contributed to open source Projects and Libraries including "matplotlib"

## **Projects on Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence**

**Artificial Intelligence Based Control of Self Driving Car** Lane detection and Steering angle prediction for road vehicles, prototyped on Raspberry Pi and Arduino.

**BetterBinge** Using Template Matching algorithm from Open CV library, to automatically Skip Intro, Ads, End Credits while streaming on services like Netflix, Amazon Prime, YouTube. <u>BetterBinge</u>

#### **Relevant Skills**

Frontend Development

User Experience Optimization

**UI UX Design** 

**Problem Solving** 

**Graphic Design** 

**Query research** Advance Query research using Google

### **Software Skills**

Word | PowerPoint (Advance Level)

Adobe XD | Photoshop | Figma

#### **Hobbies**

Cooking

**Playing Piano** 

**Teaching** 

Open Mics (Standup Comedy)

Formula 1 Racing enthusiast

Music Production and Mixing